ELENA HARAN

FULL-STACK WFB DEVELOPER

- @ elenaharan@gmail.com
- https://www.linkedin.com/in/elenaharan/
- https://github.com/elenaharan
- https://elenaharan.github.io/Portfolio_site/

SUMMARY

Junior full-stack web developer with experience in creating responsive web applications from scratch for both desktop and mobile applications. Able to use JavaScript both on the server side using Node.js and Express to build APIs, and to create complex user interfaces on the client side using such frameworks as Angular and React. Experience in building Progressive Web Applications (PWAs), Single Page Applications (SPA), and native mobile applications with React native.

C	\vee	ш	I C
. ``	\sim	ш	1.5

FRONT-FND

HTML / CSS

JAVASCRIPT

REACT

ANGULAR

REACT NATIVE

BOOTSTRAP

JQUERY REDUX

RECHARTS

BACK-END

NODE.JS

REST API

AWS PostgreSQL

MongoDB

EXPRESS

POSTMAN

WEB DEVELOPMENT EXPERIENCE

FULL-STACK DEVELOPER | CareerFoundry | Angular application written in TypeScript

- December 2021 January 2022
 - o built the client-side for an application called myFlix using Angular
 - o implemented routing between the front end and the existing server-side code (REST API and database)
 - o created supporting documentation using TypeDoc View live demo and project on GitHub

FULL-STACK DEVELOPER | CareerFoundry | React Native mobile application

November - December 2021

- o built a chat app for mobile devices using React Native
- programmed Google Firestore Database to store chat conversations
- produced chat interface and functionality using Gifted Chat Library View project on GitHub

FULL-STACK DEVELOPER | CareerFoundry | React Serverless Progressive Web Application October – November 2021

- o developed serverless PWA with React using a test-driven development (TDD) technique
- coordinated application with Google Calendar API to fetch upcoming events
- implemented two charts using Recharts for data visualization View live demo and project on GitHub

FULL-STACK DEVELOPER | CareerFoundry | Single-page application with React

August - September 2021

- o created React application using the MERN (MongoDB, Express, React, Node.js) tech stack
- implemented Bootstrap as a UI library
- used React Redux to implement Flux design pattern in the React app View project on GitHub

LANGUAGES

BACK-END DEVELOPER | CareerFoundry | REST API and non-relational database July 2021

JAVASCRIPT

- o built server-side component of a "movies" web application
- o created a REST API and database using the MERN tech stack
- o implemented both basic HTTP authentication and JWT/Token-based authentication View project on GitHub

TYPESCRIPT

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

TEACHING ASSISTANT | St. Stephen's CE Primary School

September 2020 – present

- o assist the class teacher in devising strategies and implementing action plans to overcome challenges
- o aid pupils to learn as effectively as possible, both in group situations and individually
- o maintain a supportive relationship with pupils and promote self-esteem and positive attitude towards learning

ENGLISH AS A FOREIGN LANGUAGE TEACHER | Katherine and King's College of London May 2019 – September 2020

- o taught general English lessons to international adults and juniors
- o developed and taught test-preparation courses to local and international groups of students from South Korea, Italy, and China
- o delivered demonstration lessons for online training course for teachers

EDUCATION

CareerFoundry, FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPMENT

June 2021 – January 2022

Berlin, Germany

- o built responsive portfolio website that showcase projects developed throughout the course
- o implemented every step involved in producing a complete web application, such as project planning, building the server, development of codebase, version control, testing, writing documentation and deployment
- acquired in-demand full-stack programming skills including building progressive web applications and single page applications

View Course Curriculum

M.A. in Linguistics, University of Colorado at Boulder Boulder, Colorado USA

August 2008 – May 2010